netdevgroup.com 2018-08-18

# NDG Privacy Policy

Network Development Group, Inc. (“NDG”) is committed to protecting the privacy of personal information provided in connection with the delivery of our online services and online courses and content (collectively, the “Services”) made available at www.netdevgroup.com and/or other web sites owned or controlled by NDG (the “Sites”). This Privacy Policy provides an overview of the terms surrounding use of this information and discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices in connection with the Services. It does not apply to personal information that may be acquired by NDG in other ways. 

#### Information Collected

Users may be required to provide their first and last name, e-mail address, address, student ID, and other information when registering and using the Services. For certain services, NDG reseller FastSpring may require credit card and other payment information, but NDG does not retain credit card information. For information about the Privacy Policy of our credit card processor, [ please click here](https://fastspring.com/privacy/). NDG may also collect information regarding your use of the Services, including the results of assessments made through the Services. 

If your Services are being provided as part of a course delivered by a school or other third party providing training or education, then your information may be shared with that school or third party. This information is intended for use by your course instructor in compliance with applicable laws regarding privacy of student information and grades. 

The Services may contain collaboration tools to allow for group projects and other communications. These tools may allow users to see other users’ personal information including account/student name, lab reservation time, and other information. Any additional personal information that you communicate with other users of the Services through collaboration or communication tools is your own choice. 

NDG uses "cookies" to identify users when they are logged into the Services. A cookie is a data file that a web site writes and sends to your computer when you visit the Sites. The Services may not be fully functional unless you accept use of Internet cookies. This information is used to identify who you are when you make a request to the Services. If you allow your browser to accept NDG cookies, a cookie is set and trusted when you return to the Services after visiting an external site. After you log out of the services, the cookie is deleted. We are not responsible for the use of cookies by other web sites that may be accessed through us. 

NDG gathers information about its users collectively and logs IP addresses, session sources, and other data that track access to the Sites. We analyze these logs to better understand aggregate behavior and to monitor performance of our Services. The logs are analyzed to ascertain the overall aggregate trends they reveal about our users, but not as a means of tracking the behavior of individual users outside our Sites. This information is used for the purposes of maintaining and improving the Services, and expanding its capabilities. 

#### Use and Disclosure of Collected Information

We do not use or share your personal information with others except as indicated in this Privacy Policy. 

NDG will use your personal information to provide the Services to you, alert you of new Services features and enhancements, enhance and test the Services, respond to your support issues, respond to instructor’s questions, and/or notify you of upgrade opportunities, promotions, and special offers. You agree that we may communicate with you via email and similar technologies for any purpose relating to the Sites or the Services. 

We take diligent efforts to not divulge user information to unauthorized individuals. We strive to ascertain whether authorized persons are able to access the information correctly and to inform instructors how to access it. 

NDG may use aggregate information to determine the demographics of our users and to distribute statistics and general marketplace information about NDG. These demographics will always represent aggregate information and will not identify a specific user. 

NDG may disclose your information to NDG third-party partners who provide related products and services. These partners may use your information to issue you a badge for completion of a course or provide your information about related products and services. These partners are required to target their offers carefully. You may withdraw your consent for disclosure of your personal information to these third-party partners by providing notice to NDG at the address or email address noted below. 

NDG may also disclose personal information: 

  * when we have your permission to do so; or
  * to companies who work for NDG to provide one or more parts of the Services or that provide related administrative functions (such as support Services, web analytics, and fraud detection). These third parties may have access to your personal information; if they do, this access is only so that they may perform these tasks on our behalf and they are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose; or 
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (1) comply with a legal process or law, or to respond to a government request for information, (2) enforce the terms of use or other agreements, (3) respond to claims that any content on the Sites or Services violates the rights of third parties, or that otherwise arise from your use of the Services, or (4) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of NDG, its users, or the public. 

#### Children

NDG does not knowingly allow children under the age of sixteen (16) to sign up for an account on the Services or to otherwise disclose any of their personal information to us. If you are under 16 years old, please do not use or access our Services. We do not intend to collect information about children under the age of 16. If we later obtain actual knowledge that a user is under 16 years of age, we will take steps to remove that user’s information from our systems. If you are the parent or guardian of a child under 16 whom you believe has disclosed personal information to us, please contact us at [ ](mailto:support@netdevgroup.com) , so that we may delete and remove the child’s information from our systems. 

#### Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving certain communications from us, by emailing us at [ ](mailto:support@netdevgroup.com) . In addition, all marketing e-mails from NDG will provide you with the opportunity to unsubscribe from future marketing mailings. Even if you opt out of such mailings, however, we reserve the right to send you e-mail and other communications to disclose maintenance and other Services-related issues. 

You may also let us know also if you want to opt-out of receiving marketing e-mails from our business partners who have received information about you through our Services. We will use best reasonable efforts to pass along this request to our partners, but it is the sole responsibility of our partners to comply with your request. 

#### Your Rights

You may withdraw your consent for disclosure of your personal information to NDG business partners by providing notice to NDG at the address or email address noted below. 

You have the right to access and edit, update or delete your personal information by logging onto the Site and accessing your account information through the account profile component of the Services. You may contact us with any questions or if you need assistance in updating or deleting your personal information. 

You can ask us for a copy of your personal data in machine readable form. 

#### Third-party Sites and Services

The Sites and Services may contain links and other connections to other web sites, services or internet information. We have no responsibility for the privacy practices of other web sites and services, including the web sites and services of our advertisers or business partners. 

The fact that we may link to a website or present an advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over any third party website or service. Other web sites or services may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites and services associated with the Services. 

#### Legal Requirements

We intend to protect your privacy to the fullest extent possible as described in this policy while also fulfilling our responsibility to uphold all applicable laws and regulations. Due to potential legal requirements and other possible circumstances, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed or accessed in ways not otherwise described in this policy. We may be compelled under law to disclose information to government or third parties under certain circumstances or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Further, we can, and you hereby authorize us to, disclose any information to law enforcement or other government officials that we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate in compliance with the law and/or government requests. 

#### United States

The Services is hosted in the United States. If you are accessing the Sites or Services from outside the United States, please be advised that through your continued use of the Sites or Services, which is governed by U.S. law and this Privacy Policy, you are transferring your personal information to the United States and you consent to that transfer. The United States may not have the same data protection laws as your country. However, to the extent that Regulation (EU) 2016/679, the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) applies to you, NDG will comply with GDPR. 

#### Security Measures

We have implemented reasonable and industry standard security measures on the Sites to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the personal information under our control. Additionally, NDG takes reasonable steps to ensure that our third party business partners, including our hosting partners, provide sufficient protection for personal information. 

You acknowledge that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, and that we cannot guarantee absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Sites and Services, you may contact us. 

#### Compliance With Laws

NDG will take reasonable steps to avoid any violation any privacy rights of users as established by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA), and any applicable US state law governing student privacy, and other relevant state, federal, and international laws. 

#### Changes

NDG will post any changes to this Privacy Policy on the Sites. Your continued use of the Sites and Services constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions. 

If you have any questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us or write to: 

Network Development Group, Inc.  
PO Box 13169,  
2 Davis Drive  
Research Triangle Park, NC 27709  

If you believe you have not received an appropriate response from us regarding your question or complaint, you may contact the applicable supervisory authority below based on your residence: 

  * [ Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) ](https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/task.html)

Last Revised: May 2018
